tafeqld.edu.au 2018-03-23

# Tafe Queensland Privacy Policy - TAFE Queensland

**1     PURPOSE**

TAFE Queensland (ABN 72 898 805 093) is a provider of further education and training in Queensland offering practical, industry-relevant training to students across six regions; TAFE Queensland Brisbane, TAFE Queensland Gold Coast; TAFE Queensland East Coast, TAFE Queensland North, TAFE Queensland South West and TAFE Queensland SkillsTech. On 1 July 2013, TAFE Queensland was established as an independent statutory body under the TAFE Queensland Act 2013.

TAFE Queensland (referred to as we, us or our) has implemented this Privacy Policy to provide individuals with information about how we hold and use personal information we collect.

By providing your personal information to TAFE Queensland, you consent to its use, storage and disclosure in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you wish to make any inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy, you should contact us using the contact details specified in section 4.8.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information. This document sets out our policy on how we will manage your personal information.

**2     SCOPE**

This policy applies to all TAFE Queensland employees, associates, students and stakeholders.

**3     DEFINITIONS**

Personal information is information or an opinion, whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an identified individual or an individual who is reasonably identifiable.

Examples of personal information include your name, postal address, telephone number and email address.

**4     POLICY DETAIL**

**4.1     How do we collect your personal information?**

We collect personal information about you in a number of ways, including:

  * Directly from you, for example, when you:
    * enrol to complete a course at TAFE Queensland;
    * provide information to us in person or by phone, email, in an application form, request for VET FEE-HELP or VET Student loan form, or competition entry form;
    * submit information through our web sites (including without limitation <http://tafeqld.edu.au/>; [http://tafebrisbane.edu.au/](http://tafeqld.edu.au/); <http://tafegoldcoast.edu.au/>; <http://tafeeastcoast.edu.au/>; <http://tafesouthwest.edu.au/>; <http://tafenorth.edu.au/>; [http://tafeskillstech.edu.au](http://tafeskillstech.edu.au/)); and
  * From third parties, such as:
    * TAFE Queensland's commercial partners;
    * social media sites such as Facebook and Twitter when you contact or otherwise engage with TAFE Queensland through these social media sites; and
    * third party service providers, to provide or facilitate your enrolment at TAFE Queensland.

Where we engage with you multiple times over a short period in relation to the same matter, we may not provide you with a separate notice about privacy each time we engage with you.

The personal information collected and held about you includes but is not limited to:

  * your name, address, email address, age, gender, tax file number, citizenship, unique student identifier, occupation, contact information;
  * information about your education history and other related information if you are a student registered with us;
  * payment details, such as your credit card details;
  * details of courses undertaken with us;
  * background checks including police checks and working with children checks if you apply for employment or other related positions;
  * health and sensitive information as described in section 4.3 below; and
  * other information provided voluntarily by you, for example in response to surveys or competitions.

**4.2     How do we use your personal information?**

TAFE Queensland may use your personal information for the primary purpose for which it was collected and secondary purposes either related to the primary purpose, or as otherwise set out in this Privacy Policy. Such primary and secondary purposes may include, without limitation, use of your personal information to:

  * Process any application for enrolment you might submit to us;
  * Process a VET FEE-HELP or VET Student loan request and submit information to the Australian Government - Department of Education and Training;
  * Verify your identity;
  * Develop student registers to enable us to communicate with you and any nominated parent/guardian;
  * Process any job application you might submit to us;
  * Develop, run, administer and promote competitions, programs, activities and other events run by us, including promotion on social media;
  * Market and promote products, services, merchandise and special offers made available by us or our respective corporate partners;
  * Administer and manage our respective web sites and provide you with access to those web sites;
  * Share your personal information with our respective commercial partners;
  * Administer and manage any account you may hold with us;
  * Keep you informed of news and information relating to TAFE Queensland, including by distributing newsletters, publications and other communication via various mediums including direct mail, email, SMS and MMS messages;
  * If you are an employee or other representative of a customer to which we provide our products and services or a supplier or service provider to us, to communicate with you about your or your employer's engagement with us and otherwise as specified in this Privacy Policy;
  * Research and develop new programs, activities and other events relating to education and other services; and

You consent to us using your personal information in the above ways. You can contact us using the contact details specified in section 4.8 if you do not want to receive marketing information (such as our newsletters, publications and other communications) or use the unsubscribe option within electronic communications. However, you cannot opt out of receiving administrative messages in relation to any course in which you are currently enrolled.

We may collect and use your personal information for other purposes not listed above. If we do so, we will make it known to you at the time we collect or use your personal information.

We do not otherwise use or disclose your personal information without your permission, unless the disclosure is:

  * in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any agreement you enter into with us; or
  * required or authorised by law, including without limitation the Information Privacy Principles under the _Information Privacy Act 2009 (Qld)_.

If you choose not to provide your personal information to us for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, you may not be able to enrol in courses or receive certain products and services, and we may not be able to undertake certain activities for you, such as enrolling you in a course or providing you with requested information, products or services.

**4.3     Health and sensitive information**

In some circumstances we may collect:

  * Information about your health; or
  * Other sensitive information about you (for example, information about your racial or ethnic origin).

We will collect health and sensitive information about you only if you directly provide that information to us.

We may use health information about you to ensure that any education programs in which you participate are run safely and in accordance with any special health needs you may have, for insurance purposes and otherwise as required or authorised by law..

In addition, we may use de-identified health information and other de-identified sensitive information to:

  * carry out research;
  * prepare submissions to government or a government body; or
  * otherwise plan events and activities.

De-identified information is information which has been aggregated or otherwise anonymised so that it cannot be used to identify you or any other individual.

**4.4     When do we disclose your personal information?**

We may disclose your personal information to:

  * If you are a school based apprentice or VET in Schools student - your school, the Queensland Curriculum and Assessment Authority and the Queensland Tertiary Admissions Centre;
  * If you are enrolled in training paid for by your employer - to your employer;
  * If you are enrolled with TAFE Queensland and undertaking training with another organisation (including other training providers, community organisations, or schools) - the organisation with which you are undertaking training;
  * If you are enrolled with TAFE Queensland in a program eligible for articulation through a higher education delivery partner (for example the University of Canberra), and/or intend to continue study via a pre-arranged articulation pathway (for example you are studying a dual qualification with TAFE Queensland and a higher education provider) - the higher education provider;
  * If you are under the age of 18 - your parent/guardian (unless you have formally advised TAFE Queensland not to provide this information);
  * If you are an international student - the parties outlined in the terms and conditions agreed upon accepting a place with TAFE Queensland;
  * Government Authorities and Agencies including but not limited to the National Centre for Vocational Education and for VET FEE-HELP and VET Student Loans purposes the Department of Education and Training and the Tuition Assurance Scheme;
  * Third parties that we have engaged to carry out functions and activities on our behalf (such as other education providers, our website hosts, trade suppliers, independent contractors and other third party service providers) or that we otherwise work with to provide our education programs;
  * Our commercial partners;
  * Our professional advisers, including our accountants, auditors and lawyers;
  * Our insurers; and
  * Otherwise as required or authorised by law.

Some of your personal information may be transferred, stored, processed or used overseas by us or by third party service providers. This may happen if we outsource certain activities overseas or if transactions, information, services or products have an overseas connection. You consent to the collection, use, storage, and processing of your personal information outside of Australia.

In particular, your personal information may be disclosed to third party service providers which may store your personal information in India, the USA, the UK, and such other countries in which those parties or their, or our, computer systems may be located from time to time, where it may be used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, without us being responsible under the _Information Privacy Act 2009 (Qld)_ for such use (or for any breach). In these circumstances, you consent to the collection, use, storage and processing of your personal information in those countries. Where such parties are located overseas, you may have rights to enforce such parties' compliance with applicable data protection laws, but you may not have recourse against those parties under the _Information Privacy Act 2009 (Qld)_ in relation to how those parties treat your personal information.

**4.5     Our web sites**

When you visit our web sites, our systems may record certain information about your use of those web sites (such as which web pages you visit and the time and date of your visit). We use this information to help analyse and improve the performance of our web sites.

In addition, we may use "cookies" on our web sites. Cookies are small text files that help a web site to remember your preferences and improve your experience of using that web site. Using cookies is standard practice for most large web sites. In some cases, the cookies that we use may collect some personal information about you. We will treat this information in the same way as other personal information we collect about you. If you prefer, you may be able to disable cookies on your internet browser. However, if you do so, you will not be able to enjoy the enhanced user experience that our cookies offer.

We may engage third parties, to help analyse how our web sites are used. This analysis is performed using data collected from the web sites, including by using cookies which are stored on your computer. The information generated is used to create reports about the use of our web sites, and these third parties may store this information. However, this information is not intended to and will generally not include any personal information. If you would prefer that these third parties do not collect even any anonymous data about how you use our web sites, you may be able to opt-out. Please contact us using the contact details specified in section 4.8 for more information.

Web beacons are images that originate from a third party site to track visitor activities. We use web beacons to track the visiting patterns and browsing habits of individuals accessing our website. This information is not intended to and will generally not include any personal information, and we will not use the information to identify any individual.

We may also collect Internet Protocol (IP) addresses relating to you when you access and use the web sites. IP addresses are assigned to computers on the internet to uniquely identify them within the global network of computers which makes up the internet. We may collect and manage IP addresses for internet session management and security purposes.

Some of the content on our web sites may include links to third party websites or applications made available by third parties, such as social media buttons or links that allow you to share content or links to our website through the relevant third party platforms. These third party links or applications themselves may facilitate collection of information by those third parties, through your interaction with the applications and sometimes even if you do not interact directly with them. We are not responsible for the technical operation of these links or applications or the collection and use practices of the relevant third parties. Please visit the relevant third party websites to understand their privacy practices and options they may make available to you in relation to their collection of your personal information.

**4.6     Accuracy of your personal information**

We take all reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, we rely on the accuracy of personal information as provided to us both directly and indirectly.

If you find that the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date, please contact us immediately (our contact details are set out in section 4.8 below) and we will take reasonable steps to ensure that it is corrected.

Current TAFE Queensland students have access to view their personal details though the TAFE Queensland Student Self Service website.

**4.7     How can you access the personal information we hold about you?**

Please refer to the Right to Information section of our website located at <http://tafeqld.edu.au/about-us/rti.html>.

Current TAFE Queensland students have access to update their personal details though the TAFE Queensland Student Self Service website.

**4.8     How to contact us**

If you:

  * have any questions in relation to this Privacy Policy or our Personal Information handling processes;
  * wish to make a complaint in relation to a breach of your privacy;
  * would like to opt out of direct marketing; or
  * would like to correct your Personal Information held by us,

you can write to:

  * TAFE Queensland's Privacy Officer at PO Box 161 City East Qld 4002 or email [TAFE.Communication@tafeqld.edu.au](mailto:TAFE.Communication@tafeqld.edu.auu);

We take all privacy complaints seriously and will investigate your complaint in a confidential manner. You will be informed of the outcome of the investigation within a reasonable period of time.

**4.9     Changes to this Privacy Policy**

From time to time, we may need to change this Privacy Policy to reflect our changing business practices. We will notify you of any amendments by posting an updated version of this Privacy Policy on the TAFE Queensland website (<http://tafeqld.edu.au/>).

_Last Updated: June 2017_
